Guide to the American Slavery Documents Collection, 1757-1924 and undated RL.11093
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Slavery Series, 1757-1867; undated; 1
  - Life insurance policy for one slave: Mary, 34 y.o., taken out by Bertha Buck, Charter Oak Life Insurance Policy, Savannah [Ga.], 1860 May 19; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Documents detailing the prices of Betts and Gregory slave market, list broken down by gender, age, and height, Franklin St., Richmond, [Va.?], 1860-1861; 3 items (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Bill of sale for one slave: Daphney, 22 y.o., from Samuel F. Shelton to Richard Jones, 1860 November 30 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Letter detailing the dropping and unsustainable price of slaves, from Dickinson, Hill and Co., Richmond [Va.?], 1860 December 28 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Indenture to hire slave Jenny from I.F. Torrance, Grenada, Miss., 1861 January 1 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Sheriff's notice to sell a runaway slave, at the Barren County Court, dated 1862. (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Bills of sale for one slave boy: Wash, and one slave girl: Jane, from Jacob Semly to G.L. Davidson, 1861 January 17; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Note for rental of slave man until 25 Dec. 1863 from Joseph Trout: [Cob Mam Oly] Kees, including furnishing with clothing, $90, to [name excised], Front Royal area, Va., 1862 October 8 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Document detailing gift of slaves to James A. Clark from Richard R. Wringley, after Wringley's death, 1862 November 18 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Bill of sale for one slave man: Lawson, 35 y.o., from A.M. Bogle to A. Carson, 1863 February 21 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Sale bonds for runaway slaves: Stephen, George, Sherrod, Charles, and Lewis, Barren County, Ky., 1863 March 16 - June 15 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Jailer auction of runaway slaves: George, 23 y.o., Lewis, 18 y.o., Gasper, 18 y.o., Sherrod, 16 y.o., and Charles, 28 y.o., Warren County, Ky., 1863 June 15 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Bill of sale for one slave boy: Charles, 16 y.o., Warren County, Ky., 1863 May 11 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Court documents relating to the sale of slave: Miranda, belonging to Benjamin Farmer of Murphreesborough, Tenn., Warren County, Ky., 1863 May 11 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Bill of sale for one slave boy: Andrew, $350, to A.H. Mahey and B.J. Mahey, 1863 June 1 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Court documents relating to the sale of runaway slave: Henry, belonging to James Burch of Tenn., Nelson County, Ky., 1863 June 8 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Bill of sale for one runaway slave: Rosetta, by A.B. Dyer, Ky., 1863 June 8 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Document certifying the freedom of Thomas Segen, 21 y.o., 5 ft. 11 in., by Richard F. Graves, Powhatan County, [Va.], 1863 July 6 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Court documents relating to the sale of runaway slave: John, belonging to Albert Dudley of Fayette County, Woodford County, Ky., 1863 August 3 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Court documents relating to the sale of runaway slave: Henry, belonging to James Williams of Tenn., Madison County, Ky., 1863 September 15 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Documents relating to the sale of a runaway slave, Jim, belonging to James Strong of Giles County Tenn, Warren County, Ky., 1863-1864; 7 items (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Documents relating to the sale of a runaway slave, George, belonging to Augustus Stanley of Davidson County, Tenn., Warren County, Ky., 1863-1864; 7 items (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Documents relating to the sale of a runaway slave: Amanda Adalade, belonging to Alfred Goodlon of Wilson County, Warren County, 1863-1864; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Bills of sale for two slaves: Oscar, and Harry from Stewart Buchanan to G.W. Hall, Richmond, Va., 1863 October 27; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Court documents relating to the sale of runaway slave: Bob, belonging to Jacob Falk of Morgan County Ala., Woodford County, Ky., 1864 January 4 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Court documents relating to the sale of runaway slave: Edmund, Adair County, Ky., 1864 January 5 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Court documents relating to the sale of runaway slave: Dick, belonging to John Rizer and John S. Dixon of Louisville, Nelson County, Ky., purchased by John F. Queen for $265, 1864 January 11 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Court documents relating to the sale of runaway slave: Anthony, belonging to Peter Ideley of Adams County, Miss., Shelby County, Ky., 1864 February 8 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Sale bond of runaway slave boy: John, by George Pollard, Hanisan County, Ky., 1864 February 8 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Bill of sale for one slave man: Arthur, $5500, from S. Cohen to Mr. Muse, Richmond, Va., 1864 February 17 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Court documents relating to the sale of runaway slave: George, belonging to John Anderson of Nashville, Tenn., Nelson County, Ky., 1864 March 14 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Letter for D.P. Robb concerning court proceedings on two runaway slaves, Versailles, Ky., 1864 April 1 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Court documents relating to sale of slave boy: Jim, from Sheriff of Adair County, Adair Co., Ky., 1864 April 4 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Documents relating to the sale of runaway slave, Felix, belonging to William Boxdell of Tenn. Warren County, Ky., 1864 April 26 and 1864 June 4; 7 items (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Documents relating to the sale of runaway slave, Frank, belonging to William Kimble of Davidson County, Tenn., $105.40, Warren County, Ky., 1864 April 8 and 1864 June 4; 6 items (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Documents relating to the sale of runaway slave: Charles, belonging to William Ramsey of Tenn., Warren County, Ky., 1864 June 4; 6 items (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Documents detailing the deposit of $1435.53 for the use of the Treasurer of Ky. For three slaves, was 30 cents short. From J.H. Rose to W.J. Samuels, auditor, by J.H. Rose, Bowling Green, Ky., 1864 June 6; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Cancelled bond for one slave: John, $752.25, cancelled by court because John had disease and died, Livingston County, Ky., 1864 June 6 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Letter from James Rose to W.L. Samuels concerning runaway slaves and Maxwell's Bond, 1864 November 2 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Order quashing sale bond of Col. C. Maxwell, Bowling Green, Ky., 1865 February 2 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Return of check, $145.33, regarding case of slave: Anthony, 1865 May 6 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Receipt from William Morrison for W. Butler, $20, for advertising Jim, a runaway slave, 1865 May 15 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Statement of public sale for runaway slave boy: M., by J.W. Cade, Livingston County, Ky., 1865 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Statement of public sale for two runaway slaves: William and John, Livingston County, Ky., 1865 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Bills of sale for two runaway slaves: Abner and John, Livingston County, Ky., 1865 May 24; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Bills of sale for one runaway slave: Anthony, Shelby County, Ky., 1865 May; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Receipts for [from the payments paid by] W. Butler, Adair County, Ky. for paying fees for runaway slave Jim, 1865 June 20 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Documents relating to the sale of two runaway slaves, Emma and Francis, belonging to Allen Butler of Crittenden County, Shelby County, Ky., 1865-1866; 5 items (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Court documents relating to the sale of a runaway slave, Henry Fisher, belonging to Charles Ellis of Fayette County, Shelby County, Ky., 1864-1866; 7 items (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Letter regarding disagreement on slave fees and payments from J.W. Butler, Columbia, Ky., 1866 January 6 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Letter from J.W. Butler to W.T. Samuels, Esq., Columbia, Ky., 1866 January 20 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Court documents relating to the sale of runaway slave: Jeremiah, to John Mathis, Livingston County, Ky., 1866 December 4 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Letter regarding refund of purchase money for slave from James W. Cade to W.T. Samuels, Esq., Smithland, Ky., 1866 December 6 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Letter regarding the refund of money for runaway slave John from A.V. Wood to W.J. Samuels, Cadiz, Ky., 1866 December 8 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Letter from A.B. Dyer to W.T. Samuels, Cadiz, Ky. regarding the credit due him from the 1863 June sale of runaway slave Rosetta., 1867 June 17 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Letter from A.B. Dyer to Treasurer, Cadiz, Ky., regarding payment due from sale of runaway slave Rosetta. $62.35 was enclosed., 1867 July 25 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Letter from C.C. Hooks to W.T. Samuels, Esq., Cadiz, Ky., regarding the statement for runaway slave Rosetta., 1867 June 27 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Bank Book Freedman's Savings and Trust Company, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Handwritten paper, Dr. Bracking, Murfeesboro, Tenn., 1924 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Letter to W.T. Samuels, Warren County, Ky., undated (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Slave pricing sheets, undated; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - No. 1 female slave sold for $1380, undated (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - List of names of 30 slaves, undated (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Amounts acquired from sales of slaves, undated (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - List of slaves' ages, undated; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Slave prices for individual slaves, undated; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 99)